<idea-plugin>
    <id>com.hedworth.milkj</id>
    <name>MilkJ</name>
    <vendor url="https://github.com/Bigsy">Bill Hedworth</vendor>

    <description><![CDATA[
    A WYSIWYG Markdown editor for JetBrains IDEs, powered by <a href="https://milkdown.dev">Milkdown</a>. Ideal for agentic AI md PLAN editing workflows.
    <br/><br/>
    MilkJ adds a rich "what you see is what you get" editing surface for Markdown files, rendered with
    Milkdown inside an embedded JCEF browser. It appears as an editor tab right next to IntelliJ's
    built-in Markdown editor &mdash; write in WYSIWYG, then switch back to the native source/preview
    editor whenever you like.
    <br/><br/>
    Built-in Harper spell checking highlights mistakes as you write and includes an application-wide,
    persistent custom dictionary. Add project names and specialist terms directly from the correction
    popup, or manage the complete dictionary in MilkJ settings.
    ]]></description>

    <!-- Product / plugin compatibility. No dependency on the bundled Markdown plugin: MilkJ matches
         files by extension and must keep working when that plugin is disabled. -->
    <depends>com.intellij.modules.platform</depends>
    <!-- Since 2026.2 (262) the JCEF classes live in the separate bundled "Web Browser (JCEF)"
         plugin; without this dependency the MilkJ classloader can't see JBCefApp there. The alias
         only exists from 2025.3.1, so it must stay optional to keep loading on 2024.1+, where JCEF
         is part of the core platform. -->
    <depends optional="true" config-file="milkj-jcef.xml">com.intellij.modules.jcef</depends>

    <change-notes><![CDATA[
    <b>0.1.8</b>
    <ul>
        <li>Added Harper spell checking for rendered Markdown.</li>
        <li>Added a persistent custom dictionary, with quick-add actions in the correction popup and full management in MilkJ settings.</li>
        <li>Dictionary changes automatically update every open MilkJ editor.</li>
    </ul>
    <br/>
    <b>0.1.7</b>
    <ul>
        <li>No more spurious "File Cache Conflict" dialogs: MilkJ no longer writes into the document unless you actually edited in the MilkJ tab.</li>
        <li>External edits update the editor in place instead of rebuilding it (cursor and scroll are kept).</li>
        <li>Edits sync as minimal text ranges — finer undo steps and no caret jumps in the native tab.</li>
        <li>Read-only files are now read-only in MilkJ too, and a notification appears if a conflicting external change discards an unsynced edit.</li>
        <li>Works even when the bundled Markdown plugin is disabled.</li>
        <li>New "Shortcuts" reference tab next to the MilkJ editor (can be hidden in Settings | Tools | MilkJ).</li>
        <li>Mermaid diagrams render through the code-block preview panel.</li>
        <li>Compatible with 2026.2 EAP, where JCEF moved into the separate "Web Browser (JCEF)" plugin.</li>
    </ul>
    ]]></change-notes>

    <extensions defaultExtensionNs="com.intellij">
        <notificationGroup id="MilkJ" displayType="BALLOON"/>
        <applicationService serviceImplementation="com.hedworth.milkj.settings.MilkJSettings"/>
        <applicationConfigurable
                parentId="tools"
                instance="com.hedworth.milkj.settings.MilkJConfigurable"
                id="com.hedworth.milkj.settings"
                displayName="MilkJ"/>

        <!--
          Registers the Milkdown WYSIWYG editor as an additional editor tab for Markdown files.
          PLACE_AFTER_DEFAULT_EDITOR keeps IntelliJ's native Markdown editor as the default tab and
          adds "MilkJ" as a switchable tab beside it (tweak the policy in the provider).
        -->
        <fileEditorProvider implementation="com.hedworth.milkj.editor.MilkJEditorProvider"/>
        <!-- "Shortcuts" reference tab; hidden via the checkbox in Settings | Tools | MilkJ. -->
        <fileEditorProvider implementation="com.hedworth.milkj.editor.MilkJShortcutsEditorProvider"/>
    </extensions>
</idea-plugin>
